<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Alex Robertson</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/"/>
 <updated>2016-03-06T13:38:55-08:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Alex Robertson</name>
   <email>alexrson@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Jacobin Calendar App</title>
   <link href="/2016/03/05/jacobin-calendar/"/>
   <updated>2016-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>/2016/03/05/jacobin-calendar</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was reading a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Napoleon-Life-Andrew-Roberts/dp/0143127853&quot;&gt;biography of Napoleon&lt;/a&gt; and found out that for like 10 years France used their own calendar put in place by the Jacobins after the fall of the Bourbon dynasty.  I noticed that there was an app extending this calendar to the modern era, but that it wasn’t free.  I therefore decided to implement it in Swift, which had come out as a language pretty recently. I thought that it would be a good way to learn how to make iOS apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French Republican Calendar was used officially from 1793 through the end of 1805. The calendar starts with the beginning of the Republican Era and the abolition of the monarchy on September 22nd 1792. It was created by a commission headed by Gilbert Romme. Along with the adoption of the Republican calendar the Jacobins also instituted a number of other reforms with the goals of eliminating traces of Ancien Régime influence and adopting decimal unit schemes. These reforms include the metric system, decimal time and decimal currency. Over the years of French Republic and into the Napoleonic Era the more revolutionary of these reforms were eliminated partly as part of a rapprochement with the Vatican (which strongly favored the seven day week) and partly as a broader tempering of revolutionary fervor. Napoleon abolished the calendar wholesale in 1805, by which time Republicanism itself had long been a dead letter. However, the metric system of units and decimal currency and many of the reforms instututed by Napoleon as Emperor are alive and well to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jacobin-calendar/id1070882896&quot;&gt;Anyways, here’s a link to the app on the iTunes store.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexrson/jCal&quot;&gt;And here’s the source.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Initial Post</title>
   <link href="/2016/03/05/initial-post/"/>
   <updated>2016-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>/2016/03/05/initial-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why am I making a personal website/blog? I just thought I’d throw a few sentence in plain English up on the internet about my programming projects over the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
